## Kristaps Grinbergs

Curriculum Vitae

hello@kristaps.me +372 58576560 Riga, Latvia <u>github.com/fassko</u> <u>kristaps.me</u> linkedin.com/in/kristapsgrinbergs

## **About**

Experienced Apple technologies software engineer - iOS, iPadOS, watchOS, tvOS & macOS. Active contributor at Swift Weekly Brief newsletter, Apollo iOS SDK (GraphQL Swift library), various open source RxSwift libraries, Starscream and more. Conference speaker.

Executed as a co-founder at a global-scale company Qminder that serviced clients such as Uber, Lyft, At&T, Bolt, The Olympic Games and more. Author of Dodies.lv, Augi & Draugi, Weather Latvia iOS apps and Qminder tvOS & iPadOS apps.

## Experience

08/2011 - 01/2020 Qminder

Co-founder & Swift developer

Development of iOS, tvOS, iPadOS apps, AppStore optimization

11/2019 - 03/2020 Lambda School

iOS Teaching instructor

Teaching and development of the iOS course and curriculum

09/2007 - 09/2012 Tieto

PL/SQL, Ruby on Rails, Java, JavaScript developer

Development and maintenance of various projects such as Rural

State support service, SEB insurance and more

03/2003 - 09/2007 Mediaparks

Front-end developer

Development and maintenance of various front-end projects

## Education

2004 - 2008

2010 - 2012	University of Latvia PhD in Computer Science (unfinished)
2008-2010	University of Latvia  Masters degree in Computer Science

University of Latvia

Bachelors degree in Computer Science